# Lorenzo Feruglio

PhD Candidate at Politecnico di Torino

Via Baretti 26, C/O Lo Giudice
10129 Torino
Italy

\$\partial +39 3290918239\$

\times lorenzo.feruglio@gmail.com

\$\tilde{\mathbb{n}}\$ http://lorenzof.xyz

in lorenzoferuglio

#### Education

2006–2009 **Aerospace Engineering**, *Politecnico di Torino*, Torino, *Bachelor's Degree*.

2009–2012 **Aerospace Engineering**, *Politecnico di Torino*, Torino, *Master of Science*. Graduated with Honors

2014-now Aerospace Engineering, Politecnico di Torino, Torino, PhD Candidate.

2014 Exchange student at **Massachussetts Institute of Technology** for the project 'CubeSat for Space Exploration: a new paradigm for Planetary Science Missions'

2015 Visiting Student Researcher (JVSRP) at Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) for Mission Autonomy Research

## Summary

research Autonomous Space Systems, Artificial Intelligence

experience Five years and counting of hands-on experience with CubeSats

Polito CubeSat Team Leader for C&DH, AOCS and GCS design

knowledge Detailed subsystem knowledge (AOCS, C&DH)

STK, Matlab, Python, C

hands-on e-st@r CubeSat project followed from design to LEOP

projects e-st@rll CubeSat currently performing Environmental Test Campaign at ESTEC

among Fly Your Satellite! Competition 3-STAR CubeSat for GNSS Remote Sensing

## Experience

#### PhD Student - Space Engineering

2014-now Mission Autonomy Engineer, Politecnico di Torino, Torino.

Methodologies and Technologies to Improve Small Satellites Space Mission Autonomy Current field of research:

- Neural networks for image quality assessment and event detection
- Fuzzy logics for failure detection of actuators
- Definition of case studies (Interplanetary CubeSats) in order to investigate on mission autonomy-enhancing technologies
- Genetic Algorithms to optimize Multi-Attribute Tradespace Exploration problems
- Hardware-In-The-Loop testing of training algorithms for neural networks for asteroid recognition

#### Space System Engineer

2013-2014 Assistant Researcher, Politecnico di Torino, Torino.

Capture and De-Orbiting Technologies.

Field of Research:

- Development of a Simulator Technology to perform mission analyses and In-The-Loop simulations
- Research on GNC strategies for the latest phases of a rendez-vous and mating manoeuvre
- Attitude Determination and Control Algorithms testing on specific hardware (ARM architecture)
- Code development and upgrading for ADCS and OBC subsystems (e-st@rII CubeSat)
- o e-st@r-II CubeSat Subsystem and System Functional Testing

### 2012–2013 **Operation Architecture Engineer**, SES (contractor), Luxembourg.

Efficient Automation of Satellite Operations (EASO Project).

Detailed achievements:

- Development, verification and validation of automated procedures for Satellite Operations
- Payload and Bus operation procedures for the SES Orbital fleet:
  - Dynamic Satellite Simulators (Orbital)
  - AOCS, TCR, TCS, EPS, CDH procedures development and subsystem analysis by means of DSS
  - Ground Control Station Software (SCORPIO)
- o SPELL, Python, Eclipse

#### 2009–2012 Polito CubeSat Team - Team member, Politecnico di Torino, Italy.

Member of the University CubeSat Team, developing and launching 1U+ CubeSats. Detailed achievements:

- Satellite (1U and 3U CubeSat) experience:
  - System Engineering methodologies
  - ADCS, C&DH Subsystem development and testing
  - CubeSat functional testing (test definition and execution)
  - ECSS standards for software development and testing
  - Real-time OS (Salvo, RTLinux)

## Computer skills

Analysis STK, Dynamic Satellite Simulation (AOCS, Failure Detection Systems), Space Debris Mitigation

Programming C, C++, Python, Matlab/Simulink

System Eng Multi-Attribute Tradespace Exploration, Satellite System Budgets, SysML, UML, Requirements and Functional Analysis

Embedded MPS430, ARM9, Satellite Hardware-In-The-Loop Testing

Miscellaneous MS Office, Visio, LaTex

OS UNIX (Ubuntu), RTLinux, Windows

#### Languages

Italian Mother language

English Proficient

French Basic Knowledge German Basic Knowledge